Coolie Verner Papers
Coolie Verner Papers
1953-1972
Verner, Coolie
1.25 linear ft.
American educator Coolie Verner received his Ph.D. from Columbia University in 1952. He was professor of adult education at Florida State University (1953-1961) and the University of British Columbia (1961-) where he served as department chair. His awards include a Fulbright Fellowship (1952-1953), a Canada Council Fellowship (1968-1969) and an Imago Mundi Award (1959). Papers include agendas, correspondence, drafts, programs and reports. Papers include those generated while professor at Florida State University and the University of British Columbia. There are also papers from his activities in the Canadian Association for Adult Education, the International Congress of University Adult Education, from Washington State University, and those which resulted from his writings. A significant portion of the correspondence is that of Thurman J. White.
149422
Biographical History
Coolie Verner took his doctorate from Columbia University in 1952. First affiliated as a research assistant with the Institute of Adult Education at Columbia University, he became a professor of adult education at Florida State University from 1953 to 1961. Since that time he has been a professor of adult education at the University of British Columbia, where he has served as chairman of the Department of Adult Education. His awards include a Fulbright Fellowship in 1952-53, a Canada Council Fellowship in 1968-69, and an Imago Mundi Award for 1959.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The three boxes of his papers date from 1953 to 1972. They concern a wide variety of correspondence and subject materials concerned with Florida State University, Washington State University, the University of British Columbia, the Canadian Association for Adult Education, and the International Congress of University Adult Education.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Verner, Coolie, Archives; White, Thurman J.; Canadian Association for Adult Education; Adult education; Educators, United States; Educators, Canada; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Programs (documents); Reports.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1959-1971 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1970 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Activities, 1953-1971 (Box 1)
  - Algonquin College, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - Banff Symposium, "Stimulants to Social and Economic Development in Slow Growing Regions.", 1966 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Association for Adult Education, National Conference, Vancouver, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Exams, 1962-1967 (Box 1)
  - Florida State University, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
  - International Congress of University Adult Education, Second World Conference, Montreal, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Macmillan Publishing Company, 1960-1970 (Box 2)
  - Neylan-Verner Study, undated (Box 2)
  - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Professors - Canada, 1966-1969 (Box 2)
  - St. Mark's College, Night School Directors' Workshop, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Teaching-Learning Conference at Alderbrook, 1968 (Box 2)
  - University of British Columbia
    - Committee on Extra Sessional Programs, 1962-1966 (Box 2)
    - Continuing Education Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Senate Committee on Continuing Education, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
    - Trustees' Project, 1961-1966 (Box 2)
  - University of Washington, Bureau of Community Development, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Washington Northern State Hospital, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Washington State University, Seminar in Adult Education, 1970 (Box 3)
  - White, Thurman J., 1971-1972 (Box 3)
- Writings
  - "Understanding Adult Learning and Instruction," by Coolie Verner and Catherine V. Davison, undated; draft (Box 3)